Speaker: Good evening, everyone!
Welcome to this week’s quiz.
I hope you’ve got a drink and you’re feeling confident.
Here are a few rules, as always.
You’ll hear each question twice.
Write your answers on your answer sheets,
and remember: you mustn’t use your phone to Google any of the answers!
We might even get a fair result that way, who knows?!
And lastly: please remember to write your team name on your answer sheets.
Right, everyone, round one – sports!
Question one: Which English football team plays at Old Trafford?
Which English football team plays at Old Trafford?
Two: How many events are there in the decathlon?
How many events are there in the decathlon?
Three: How many times did Usain Bolt win the Olympic one hundred metres race?
How many times did Usain Bolt win the Olympic one hundred metres race?
Four: Which is the biggest, a football, a volleyball, or a basketball?
Which is the biggest, a football, a volleyball, or a basketball?
Five: Who won the men’s singles at Wimbledon seven times
between two thousand and three and two thousand and twelve?
Who won the men’s singles at Wimbledon seven times
OK – next round… music.
Question one: What’s the name of the lead singer in the band Coldplay?
What’s the name of the lead singer in the band Coldplay?
Two: Which Italian opera singer became blind
at the age of twelve after a football accident?
Which Italian opera singer became blind
Three: How many strings does a violin have?
How many strings does a violin have?
Four: In which country did the pop group Abba form in nineteen seventy-two?
In which country did the pop group Abba form in nineteen seventy-two?
Five: What was Beethoven’s first name?
What was Beethoven’s first name?
And the final round is Geography.
Question one: In which European city could you visit the Doge’s Palace and St Mark’s Square?
In which European city could you visit the Doge’s Palace and St Mark’s Square?
Two: Which rainforest produces over twenty per cent of the world’s oxygen?
Which rainforest produces over twenty per cent of the world’s oxygen?
Three: Which is the only city in the world that is in two separate continents?
Which is the only city in the world that is in two separate continents?
Four: What is the capital of the Republic of Ireland?
What is the capital of the Republic of Ireland?
Five: Angel Falls is the world’s highest waterfall.
Which country is it in?
Angel Falls is the world’s highest waterfall.
OK, time for the answers.
Swap your answer sheets please.
Here are the answers for Round one: Sport.
Which English football team plays at Old Trafford?
Manchester United.
Two: How many events are there in a decathlon?
Ten.
Three: How many times did Usain Bolt win the Olympic one hundred metres race?
Three.
Four: Which is the biggest, a football, a volleyball, or a basketball?
A basketball.
Five: Who won the men’s singles at Wimbledon seven times
between two thousand and three and two thousand and twelve?
Roger Federer.
Music.
Question one: What’s the name of the lead singer in the band Coldplay?
Chris Martin.
Two: Which Italian opera singer became blind
at the age of twelve after a football accident?
Andrea Bocelli.
Three: How many strings does a violin have?
Four.
Four: In which country did the pop group Abba form in nineteen seventy-two?
Sweden.
Five: What was Beethoven’s first name?
Ludwig.
And finally… Geography.
Question one: In which European city could you visit the Doge’s Palace and St Mark’s Square?
Venice.
Two: Which rainforest produces over twenty per cent of the world’s oxygen?
The Amazon.
Three: Which is the only city in the world that is in two separate continents?
Istanbul.
Four: What is the capital of the Republic of Ireland?
Dublin.
Five: Angel Falls is the world’s highest waterfall.
What country is it in?
Venezuela.
OK, add up the scores and bring the answer sheets to me…
OK,
and the winners are…